Welcome to our training on the UK to US partnered carrier program.
Today we will go over how to create a shipment using the UK to US partnered carrier program and
how this can benefit eligible selling partners.
The UK to US partnered carrier program offers air express shipping options to ship the fulfillment
by Amazon small parcels directly from UK warehouses to US fulfillment centers.
The UK to US partnered carrier program helps reduce complexity by supporting selling partners with
more automated booking processes, shipment tracking and payments all within Seller Central.
You could have the ability to replenish your inventory in the US without having to search
for other shipping options outside of Seller Central.
Now let's look at how to book a shipment.
Before creating your shipment, please check if your product is prohibited or requires
additional documentation.
To create a shipment, you go to manage inventory and then click on
shipments.
Then click on send to Amazon and select the products that you would like to ship.
Prepare your inventory by first choosing the packaging type you will use to ship and click
pack individual units.
Then select the Amazon partnered carrier option.
You can then select
your shipping date to confirm the pick up drop off date and click on get shipping cost to confirm
the ship date.
Now select air express as shipping mode and shipping carrier.
Then click on continue
to shipping parties.
Now you can enter the company name tax identification number, contact details
and commodity description.
Then select your pick up slot with the shipping carrier.
Once this has
been completed, review the terms and conditions.
If you agree, please click accept changes and
confirm shipping.
Once the shipment is confirmed, print out the box labels and attach to each package.
Fill out the commercial invoice.
You can find a template in the shipment creation guide.
Send the invoice to the email address below this video and print out a hard copy to hand to UPS.
It's best to have three copies of the invoice printed.
Once the commercial invoice has been
emailed and printed, hand over the packages to your courier.
You can organize to have them picked
up from your warehouse or you can drop it at your nearest shipping carrier station.
Thank you for watching this video.
Please be sure to check through the steps.
For more information, click on the links below the video.
We wish you all the best and happy
selling in the U.
S.